

# Marc-Ryan Guerin

### **Professional Summary**

Dedicated Finance Executive with a combined 8 years of experience in finance management and operation management. Hands-on leader with strong business acumen and analytical mindset to identify and correct underachieving trends. Interested in identifying unique financial opportunities and risks for organizations.

# **Work History**

#### Hyatt Corporation - Development Financial Analyst

Chicago, IL

09/2018 - Current

- Evaluated potential development projects and multi-asset acquisitions.
- Conducted due diligence.
- Supported Corporate Transaction Group.
- Prepared financial analysis of single units or portfolios in support of new brand development or repositioning.
- Presented analytical results for senior management decision-making.
- Drove operational improvements resulting in savings and improved profit margins.

#### **Hyatt Corporation - Area Manager**

San Diego, CA

05/2017 - 09/2018

- Develop labor-management strategies focusing on improving productivity.
- Managed quality assurance program, including on-site evaluations, internal audits, and customer surveys.
- Saved over \$3 Million dollars by implementing cost-saving initiatives that addressed long-standing problems.

#### **Hyatt Regency - Assistant Director of Outlets**

Long Beach, CA

04/2016 - 05/2017

- · Managed payroll & scheduling.
- Preserve excellent levels of internal and external customer service.
- Lead F&B team by attracting, recruiting, training, appraising talented personnel.



marcryan1992@gmail.com (562) 508-3132 Chicago, IL 60661

- https://marcryanguerin.com/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/marcryan-guerin-7442a198/

#### Skills

- Financial accounting systems development
- Financial controls development
- Financial auditing
- Commercial strategy development
- Software development proficiency
- Financial data assessments
- Recommendation development
- Web development expertise
- Oracle Peoplesoft Financials
- Financial model building
- Real estate development
- Residential real estate development
- Financial budgeting and reporting

- Drove operational improvements which resulted in savings and improved profit margins.
- Increased customer satisfaction by 40% by implementing training programs.

#### InterContinental - Assistant Manager

Cannes, France

04/2015 - 08/2015

- Established internal databases and record management systems to enhance accuracies and integrity of all documentation and data.
- Submitted reports to senior management to aid in business decisionmaking and planning.
- Monitored cash intake and deposit records, increasing accuracy and reducing discrepancies.

#### **Hyatt Regency - Front Desk Supervisor**

Paris, France

04/2014 - 08/2014

- Trained new staff on correct procedures, compliance requirements, and performance strategies.
- Provided guests with above-and-beyond service, including making outside venue reservations and setting up tours.
- Performed concierge services for guests as needed.

#### **Hyatt Regency - Front Desk Supervisor**

Newport Beach, CA

05/2013 - 08/2013

- Trained new staff on correct procedures, compliance requirements and performance strategies.
- Provided guests with above-and-beyond service, including making outside venue reservations and setting up tours.
- Created lasting relationships with guests that built loyalty and drove hotel revenue.

#### Ramada Inn - Assistant Hotel Manager

Costa Mesa, CA

09/2010 - 05/2013

- Established internal databases and record management systems to enhance the accuracy and integrity of all documentation and data.
- Booked large groups for weddings, seminars, conferences, and other events, providing the best available room rates.

#### Education

09/2018

**Cornell University** 

Ithaca, NY

Certification: Real Estate & Asset

Management

01/2016

Vatel International Hotel & Tourism

**Business School** 

Nimes, France

Bachelor of Science: International Hotel

&Tourism Business

08/2013

California State University of Long

Beach

Long Beach, CA

**Transfer**: International Business

Management

## Languages

French - Fluent

English - Fluent

Spanish - Proficient